John Blackwell

6 804-878-9004

⊠jblackwell072588@gmail.com

Summary

Highly motived, dedicated worker with a knack for organization. Equipped with 4 years of experience managing a banquets/events department, including staffing, billing, bookings and other communications. Seeking a role as a JavaScript developer.

Skills

Problem Solving, Personnel Management, Communication, Customer Service, Multi-Tasking, Office Suite (Word, Excel, Outlook, Access, PowerPoint, Publisher), Reserve Interactive (Events Software), Social Tables (Events Software), HTML5, CSS3, Git Control Flow, Ruby, Firebase, MySQL, MongoDB, JavaScript (ES6) including Express, React and JSX, jQuery, Handlebars, Node, API interaction (AJAX, Google Maps)

Work Experience

The Commonwealth Club

Richmond, VA

Banquet Manager

May 2013 – September 2017

- Find, interview, and hire new staff members for front of house positions
- Develop and implement training programs for front of house staff
- Schedule staffing for booked events on a weekly basis
- Book and plan events of varying sizes
- Process \$2,000,000+ in customer event invoices annually
- Synchronize timing with front of house and back of house to keep events on schedule
- Oversee daily operations of banquet department
- Communicate effectively with members and staff to create a positive and cohesive environment

Bartender

September 2010 - May 2013

- Opened and closed bar area daily, including inventory, glassware, and silverware
- Ensured cleanliness of customer and employee areas of bar throughout shift
- Efficiently received and fulfilled customer orders of varying complexities
- Completed multiple simultaneous cash and credit transactions daily
- Coordinated events in the bar and dining room areas weekly
- Provided services for large events and banquets monthly

Dick's Sporting Goods

Richmond, VA

Sales Associate

August 2008 - April 2009

- Maintained sales floor inventory and organization daily across multiple departments
- Provided knowledgeable product information and suggestions to customers daily
- Processed customer purchases

Education

Advanced Degree, D.S. Freeman - 2007	Richmond, VA
Bartending Certificate, The Professional Bartending Academy- 2010	Richmond, VA
Web Development Bootcamp University of Richmond- 2018	Richmond, VA